# **Christos Kapsalis**

Full-Stack Software Developer | Software Engineer

xrikapsalis@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/christos-kapsalis-lin/ https://ckapsalis2710.github.io/portfolio/ https://github.com/ckapsalis2710 +30 694 793 4771 Athens, 16777, Greece

Full-stack software developer for 8+ years of hands-on experience across the entire development lifecycle. Front-end development in React.js, JavaScript (ES6+), CSS3, Bootstrap and HTML5. Backend development in Node.js, Java, Lua and PHP. Eager to learn new languages, technologies and undertake interesting projects. Accountable, working on schedule and comfortable working as a team member.

# **Work Experience**

## Freelance Climbing Instructor & Software Development Sabbatical

Nov 2022 - Present

- Providing climbing instruction on a freelance basis, focusing on safety and skill development for climbers of all levels.
- Pursuing advanced full-stack development training (Zero to Mastery Academy).
- Developing projects using React.js, Node.js, and modern web technologies.
- Maintaining and expanding technical knowledge during career transition period.

# Senior Technical Specialist

Dec 2021 - Oct 2022

Nokia | Athens

- Developed backend components of Altiplano Controller, an open software GUI platform connecting other Nokia's software units via RESTful APIs.
- Implemented Java-based microservices feature with JUnit testing, loaded on a Docker container and deployed on Kubernetes infrastructure.
- Managed PODs configurations and orchestrated software interactions within Kubernetes environment.
- Experience in Intent development logic, Microservices, Cloud based solutions, DevOps operations, Kibana search engine and Postman request engine.

### **Software Engineer**

Sep 2016 - Dec 2021

Nokia | Athens

- Full-stack development of WebCT (2016-2021), a software that provided a GUI to administer X-Haul microwave products. Led back-end development of WebCT in Lua and DB handling with Lua-Sqlite3.
- Implemented WebCT GUI in Javascript, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, and Bootstrap framework.
- Side project development of ASLM (2018-2021), an app that produces licenses for all X-Haul products, in Java with JUnit testing in the back-end and React.js in the front-end.
- Involved with the full circle of a feature's production. Creation and reviewing of feature's code, software architectural designs, Low Level Design, mock-ups, CuDo documents. Developing at least one feature per release while following a biannual release schedule.
- Peer reviewing of Code, Use Cases, Test Strategy and Test Cases.
- · Applied full stack Unit Testing and debugging of code.

#### Software Engineer

Jun 2015 - Aug 2016

Nokia | Athens

• Full-stack development of the FMANG application, a comprehensive monitoring and configuration management system for Nokia's FlexiNG product.

- Contributed to back-end development of new features released on a biannual schedule in Java and Java EE Development toolset (JSF/Primefaces, Spring, Hibernate, Maven, Tomcat, Jenkins, Junit), while maintaining code quality through peer reviews of code.
- Development of the front-end in JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Led complete GUI redesign initiative after company's rebranding and resolved with the help of the team a critical system-wide bug affecting application stability.

**E&V Tester** Oct 2014 - May 2015

Nokia | Athens

- Managed CI Test Suite of 400+ test cases for Nokia's LTE network gateway (FlexiNG).
- Implemented automated testing using Robot Framework with daily CI reporting.
- Enhanced testing coverage by developing new test cases and improving existing ones.

#### Web Programmer/Developer

Dec 2012 - Jan 2014

<u>Cybertechnics Interactive Communication LTD</u> | Athens

- Full-stack development of Modus CMS using PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- Managed back-end administration and development of CMS' modules and components.
- Updating and debugging CMS' code and executed database operations, upon customers requests.
- Implementated RAFM (Restricted Access File Manager) filesystem and integration of Ajaxplorer GUI into Modus CMS.

#### **Core Skills**

Front-end Development: React.js, JavaScript (ES6+), Redux, PWA, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery, Bootstrap

Back-end Development: Node.js, Express.js, Lua, Java, Spring Framework, PHP, SQL, Bash Scripting, C

DevOps & Deployment: Kubernetes, Docker, Jenkins

Version Control: Git, SVN

Data Formats & APIs: RESTful APIs, JSON, AJAX, XML, SVI

Testing: Unit Testing, JUnit, Robot Framework

Development Tools & Others: VS Code, Eclipse, Phpstorm, Sublime, Codecharge Studio, SQL Clients,

Browsers' Web Developer Tools, Postman, Balsamiq (Mockups), Wireshark, CMS, Agile

### **Education**

#### Zero To Mastery Academy

Oct 2024 - Present

Full-Stack Web Developer Career Path. Updating my knowledge on CSS, latest versions of Javascript, learning React.js, Redux, PWA, Node.js with Express.js, PostgreSQL, Machine Learning API by building web apps, incorporating all these technologies.

University of Piraeus Sep 2004 - Oct 2011

University degree - Bachelor Digital Systems & Technology Education: Computer Science

Stockholm University and KTH joint department

Jan 2009 - Jun 2009

Erasmus Exchange Student Program Knowledge Management

# Languages

Greek (Native), English (Fluent), Italian (Internediate)